<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>my private blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on my private blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Button Chaos to Python Calm: Designing My Garden House with CadQuery</title>
      <link>/post/cadquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cadquery/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always had a complicated relationship with CAD software. It’s not that I don’t appreciate the power of digital design tools—it’s just that they never seem to work with me.
If you’ve ever opened a CAD program and been confronted with a swarm of buttons, tabs, and menus—only to watch them rearrange completely after a version update—you know what I’m talking about. Most CAD tutorials aren’t much help either. They typically go something like: “Click here, then here, now switch to this tab, drag this, click this tiny icon that has moved since last version…” You get the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Demonstrated the Real Cost of Playing Eurojackpot to My Father (Using Python)</title>
      <link>/post/eurojackpot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eurojackpot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My father is an avid lottery player. Like many others, he dreams of winning the Eurojackpot and transforming his life overnight. As a programmer, I wanted to show him—using real data—how much money is actually lost over time by playing the lottery. To do this, I developed a Python script to analyze his Eurojackpot tickets and calculate the true cost of his hobby.
Motivation Playing the lottery can be entertaining, but the odds are not in your favor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing My Daughter&#39;s Mupibox Media Server with Cover Art</title>
      <link>/post/cover_art_mp3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cover_art_mp3/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing My Daughter&amp;rsquo;s MuPiBox Media Server with Cover Art My daughter loves her MuPiBox media server, which is packed with her favorite audiobooks and music. Recently, I decided to enhance her experience by adding cover art to each album. It’s a small touch, but seeing the album covers makes her browsing more enjoyable and visually appealing. Here’s how I added cover.jpg files to her MuPiBox media server.
Tools and Libraries Used To achieve this, I used Python along with some handy libraries:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Resurrected My RNS 510 to Seal the Deal (Code Finder RNS510)</title>
      <link>/post/rns510_code_finder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rns510_code_finder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;/images/rns510/rns510_1.jpg&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; style=&#34;float:left;padding:20px;border-radius:50%&#34;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upgrading your car&amp;rsquo;s stereo system is one of those things that can breathe new life into an old vehicle. That’s exactly what I did with my trusty Volkswagen Tiguan. After years of dependable service, I decided it was time to upgrade to a newer, more feature-packed system. My old RNS 510, a reliable companion on countless road trips, was ready for a new home. But as I soon discovered, selling it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be as straightforward as I thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Legal Disclosure Information in accordance with Section 5 TMG
Contact Information Name: 
Address:


Phone: 
Email: Contact Email
Responsible for content according to § 55(2) RStV 


Disclaimer Liability for Content The contents of our pages have been created with the utmost care. However, we cannot guarantee the contents&amp;rsquo; accuracy, completeness, or topicality. According to statutory provisions, we are responsible for our own content on these web pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy 1. Overview This privacy policy explains what information is collected when you visit this website, and how it is used.
2. GitHub Pages This website is hosted on GitHub Pages. GitHub may collect personal information from visitors, including logs of visitor IP addresses, to comply with legal obligations and to maintain the security and integrity of the website and service. For more information, see the GitHub Privacy Statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug streamlit app in vscode</title>
      <link>/post/debug_streamlit_in_vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/debug_streamlit_in_vscode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to share my vscode launch configuration for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/streamlit&#34;&gt;streamlit&lt;/a&gt; live debugging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use golang library with python</title>
      <link>/post/python_wrapper_for_golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/python_wrapper_for_golang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I wrote URL tokenizer in Python and the code was very similar to a Go project.
I invested some hours to find out a solution to use the Go code in python and here are my results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algo trading part 1 - how to receive price data</title>
      <link>/post/algotrade_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/algotrade_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the important challenges in algo trading is to scan 1000 and more stocks and do some magic with the price data.
But how can we get the price data?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pass by value or pointer?</title>
      <link>/post/go_pass_by_value_or_pointer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 04:12:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/go_pass_by_value_or_pointer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will describe when you should passed a type by value or pointer in Go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decrypt travis file in github repository</title>
      <link>/post/travis_decrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 01:12:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/travis_decrypt/</guid>
      <description>Travis is a very popular CI service and offers a feature for file encryption to keep your secrets. At the moment it&amp;rsquo;s not straight forward to decrypt files and therefore I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a workaround in this post.
Workaround send a file with ftp/sftp In this method we’ll update the .travis.yml in a new branch. There is a file with the name setup.tar.gz.enc that we want to decrypt and send via ftp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashing Archer c6 with OpenWrt 19.07</title>
      <link>/post/openwrt_archer_c6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/openwrt_archer_c6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Flashing OpenWrt through the OEM web interface is not always possible but we can use TFTP instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolate FritzBox network from OpenWrt guest WiFi</title>
      <link>/post/fritzbox_behind_openwrt_guest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 01:53:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fritzbox_behind_openwrt_guest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some months ago I configured a OpenWrt WiFi router behind a Fritz!Box.
A friend of mine told me that he is able to connect to other network clients outside of the OpenWrt guest WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The behavior is quite clear after a minute of reflection. The Fritz!Box is connected to the WAN port of the OpenWrt router ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>SlashGordon I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer, living in Germany, interested in nature and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here is a list of my private projects. All sources are hosted on github.
       </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>